Guide to the Benedict Anderson papers, 1965, 1998
Anderson, Benedict Anderson papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Benedict Anderson papers, 1965, 1998
14-27-4189
Benedict R. O'G. (Benedict Richard O'Gorman), Anderson, 1936-2015.
37 cubic feet
1.6 gigabytes
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Contains some of the source material used by Anderson for the Cornell Paper (A Preliminary Analysis of the October 1, 1965, Coup in Indonesia).
Also digital files that are recordings of a symposium held when Anderson retired at Thammasat University in Bangkok, Thailand in August 1998. The moderator is Kasian Tejapira, panelists include Supot Jaengraew, Seksan Prasertkul, Akin Rabhibhat, and Thanet Apornsuwan. These include discussion of Andersons influence on Thai students and what they learned from him. They include anecdotal reminiscences of the students interaction with him at his house.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor emeritus of International Studies, Cornell University and head of its Indonesian program. Anderson was born in Kunming, China in 1936 and in 1941 the family moved to California. In 1957, Anderson received a Bachelor of Arts in Classics from Cambridge University, and in 1967 he earned a Ph.D. from Cornell's Department of Government, where he studied modern Indonesia. He was well-known for his book, “Imagined Communities: Reflections on the Origin and Spread of Nationalism,” which was first published in 1983. Anderson was renowned not only for his theoretical contributions but also for his detailed examinations of language and power in Indonesia, Thailand and the Philippines.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Contains some of the source material used by Anderson for the Cornell Paper (A Preliminary Analysis of the October 1, 1965, Coup in Indonesia).
Also digital files that are recordings of a symposium held when Anderson retired at Thammasat University in Bangkok, Thailand in August 1998. The moderator is Kasian Tejapira, panelists include Supot Jaengraew, Seksan Prasertkul, Akin Rabhibhat, and Thanet Apornsuwan. These include discussion of Andersons influence on Thai students and what they learned from him. They include anecdotal reminiscences of the students interaction with him at his house.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Anderson, Benedict R. O'G. (Benedict Richard O'Gorman), (Benedict Richard O'Gorman), 1936-2015.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University. Department of Government.; Cornell University. Southeast Asia Program.
Subjects:
Communism -- Indonesia.
Places:
Indonesia -- Foreign relations -- United States.; Indonesia -- History -- Coup d'etat, 1965.; Indonesia -- Politics and government -- 1950-1966.; Thailand -- Politics and government
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Indonesia
Series II. Thailand
Series III. Philippines
Series IV. Malaysia
Series V. Miscellaneous documents and course material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Indonesia
  - Ben Anderson Research, Expression (Box 26, Folder 18)
    Correspondence (1971-2); typescript (1972); personal letters
  - Anderson Testimonial, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    Correspondence (1976); testimony (1976)
  - Anderson 1981 Fiasco, 1981 (Box 26, 27, Folder 20)
    Correspondence (1981); newspaper clippings (1981)
  - Indonesia Grey Literature 1, Undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
    Typescript draft
  - Multilingualism Papers, 1980-1991 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    Scanned typescripts (1980-1); typescript drafts (1981; 1991); theses (1981)
  - Stuff for My Lit. Article, 1918-1973 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    Scanned typescript (1918; 1970); notes on scholarly papers (1919; 1920; 1951; 1968; 1973); additional notes
  - Old Java- Miscellaneous Offprints 1, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    Typescript draft (1981)
  - Buru Writings, 1970-1978 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    Scanned typescript (1978); typescript (1970)
  - Javanese Literature, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Scanned typescripts (1970)
  - Miscellaneous Indonesian Poetry, 1933-1991 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Typescripts (1975; 1991); correspondence; publication summary; index (1933 - 1953)
  - Abbas, Hadji Siradjuddin, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Typescripts (1956-7)
  - Abdullad, Baraba, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Typescripts (1955-6)
  - Abdullah, Djadil, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Typescripts (1956; 1960)
  - Abdulmadjid, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Typescripts (1956-7; 1960)
  - Abdurachman, Miss Paramita Rahaju, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Abisudjak, Hadji Munir, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Abuprajitno (engineer), 1959-1964 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Typescripts (1959; 1964)
  - Achmadi, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    Typescripts (1956; 1959)
  - Adjitorop, Jusuf, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    Typescripts (1956)
  - Afandi, Abullah, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Akib, Hadji Moehammad, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Amran, Amung, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Anwar, Sjamsu, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    Typescripts (1957)
  - Ardiwinata, Daeng Mohammad, 1956-1978 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    Typescripts (1956-7; 1978)
  - Asmuni, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Asraruddin, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Astrawinata, Achmad (Box 27, Folder 19)
    Typescripts (1957; 1959)
  - Atmo, Sujono; Atmodarminto, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Awaluddin, Umar, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Aziz, K. R. H. Abdul, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Basah, R. Mohamad, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Basjid, Raden Abdul, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Basri, Lt. Col. Hasan, 1956-1958 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    Typescripts (1956-8)
  - Besar, Sahar Gelar Sutan, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Bili Soleman Dairo, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    Typescript (1956)
  - Bisri, Murtadji, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Cacim, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    Typescripts (1955)
  - Caley, Marthinus, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    Typescripts (1956-7; 1959)
  - Chatib, K. A., 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Dachjar, Major, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    Typescript (1957)
  - Dachlan, K. H. Mohammad, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Darmanto, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Dasuki, H. Achmad, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Des Alwi, 1956-1958 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    Typescripts (1956; 1958)
  - Dharma, Anwar, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Diah, B. M., 1957 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Dijar, Abdul Aziz, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - Djalaluddin, Dr. Sjech Hadji, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Djambek, Mohammad, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 41)
    Typescripts (1958)
  - Djambek, Mohammad Zain, 1957-1960 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    Typescripts (1957; 1960)
  - Djanizar, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - Djanuismadi, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 44)
  - Djosan, Sutan Mohammad, 1955-1957 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    Typescripts (1955-7)
  - Djunaidi, K. Hadji Muhammad (bin Abdul Azis), 1956 (Box 27, Folder 46)
  - Djunaedi, Mrs. S. Marijamah, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 47)
  - Dulmanat, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 48)
  - Duriat, R. G., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 49)
  - Dzukhri, Ajip Muchamad, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 50)
  - Edris, Mohammad Isa, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 51)
  - Faqih, Abdul Rasjid, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 52)
  - Fatah, Abdul, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 53)
  - Gandamana, Ipik, 1957-1973 (Box 27, Folder 54)
    Typescripts (1957-8; 1973)
  - Gathmyr, Abdullah Alkaff, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 55)
  - Gatot Tarunamihardja, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 56)
  - Garnida, R. Ido, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 57)
  - Ghozali, K. Achmad, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 58)
  - Ginting, Selamat, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 59)
  - Gunawan, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 60)
  - Hadharijah, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 61)
  - Hakim, Abdul, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 62)
  - Hamdani, Njonja Suzanna, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 63)
    Typescripts (1961)
  - Hamzah, Djamhur, 1956-1963 (Box 27, Folder 64)
    Typescripts (1956-7; 1963)
  - Hardi, 1957-1964 (Box 27, Folder 65)
    Typescripts (1957-8; 1964)
  - Harsono, Lt. Col., 1959 (Box 27, Folder 66)
    Typescripts (1959)
  - Harsono, Tjokroaminoto, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 67)
  - Hartojo, Lt. Col., 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 68)
  - Hasjmy, A., 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 69)
  - Hutomo, Supardan, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 70)
  - Ibnu, Parna, 1956-1958 (Box 27, Folder 71)
  - Ibnu, Col. Dr. Sutowo, 1955-1958 (Box 27, Folder 72)
    Typescripts (1955-6; 1958
  - Imanudin, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 73)
    Typescript (1955-6)
  - Imban, Zakaria, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 74)
  - Indratjaja (engineer), 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 75)
    Typescripts (1957-8)
  - Ingkiriwang, 1957-1963 (Box 27, Folder 76)
    Typescripts(1957; 1963)
  - Isa, Mohamad (Dr.), 1956 (Box 27, Folder 77)
  - Iskander, H. Mohammad Amin, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 78)
  - Ismail, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 79)
  - Jacub, Achmad, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 80)
    Typscript (1955)
  - Jahja, Daan, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 81)
  - Jasin, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 82)
  - Johannes (Prof. Engineer), 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 83)
  - Jusuf, Mohammad, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 84)
  - Kafrawi, R. Mohammad, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 85)
  - Kape, L., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 86)
  - Karim, Eny, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 87)
  - Karim, Nini, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 88)
  - Kartakusuma, Mohammad Rachmat, 1956-1967 (Box 27, Folder 89)
    Typescripts (1956; 1967)
  - Karubuy, A. B., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 90)
  - Kasim, Hasan, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 91)
  - Kasimo, I. J., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 92)
  - Katjasungkana, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 93)
  - Kosasih, Achmad (Col.), 1957 (Box 27, Folder 94)
  - Kusmuljono, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 95)
  - Kusnadi, A. Nunung, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 96)
  - Kustarjo, R. Lucas, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 97)
  - Laoh, Frits, 1955-1960 (Box 27, Folder 98)
    Typescripts (1955; 1960)
  - Latjuba, H. Mahmud, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 99)
    Typescripts (1960)
  - Leimena, Dr. J., 1961 (Box 27, Folder 100)
  - Lumbantobing, Dr. Natiar Hulman, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 101)
  - Maengkom, Gustaaf Adolf, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 102)
  - Magenda, E. J. (Lt. Col.), 1958-1978 (Box 27, Folder 103)
    Typescripts (1958; 1978)
  - Makatita, 1956-1963 (Box 27, Folder 104)
    Typescripts (1956; 1958; 1961; 1963)
  - Maladi, R., 1957-1959 (Box 27, Folder 105)
  - Malik, Adam, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 106)
  - Malik, Djamaludin, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 107)
  - Mangunpuspito, Mrs. Sunarjo, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 108)
  - Maniudin, Brodjotruno, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 109)
  - Mardanus, R., 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 110)
  - Marhaban, Sjech, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 111)
  - Mardjani, Ma'rifat, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 112)
  - Martadinata, Col., 1956-1978 (Box 27, Folder 113)
    Typescripts (1956; 1959; 1978)
  - Masjkur, Kijai Hadji, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 114)
  - Matakupan, D. S., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 115)
  - Mawardi, Mrs. Mahmudah, 1956-1961 (Box 27, Folder 116)
    Typescripts (1956; 1961)
  - Milono (former governor), 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 117)
  - Minggu, Lt. Col., 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 118)
  - Mochtar, Pak, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 119)
  - Mooy, Christoffel Joseph, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 120)
  - Mudawari, H., 1956-1964 (Box 27, Folder 121)
    Typescripts (1956-7; 1964)
  - Munadir, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 122)
  - Munir, Mohammad, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 123)
    Typescripts (1956; 1958; 1960)
  - Musaddad, Hadji Anwar, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 124)
  - Mustain, R. K. H., 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 125)
  - Muslich, Hadji, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 126)
  - Muttaqien, Engkin Zainal, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 127)
  - Nasrun, Mohammad, 1956-1967 (Box 27, Folder 128)
    Typescripts (1956-7; 1960; 1967)
  - Nazaruddin, A. R., 1955 (Box 27, Folder 129)
    Typescript (1955)
  - Nazir, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 130)
  - Ngantung, Henk, 1955-1964 (Box 27, Folder 131)
    Typescripts (1955-8; 1964)
  - Noor, Abdulgani Mohammad, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 132)
  - Noor, Cumala Adjaib, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 133)
  - Noor, Mawardir, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 134)
  - Noor, Mohammad, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 135)
  - Noor, P., 1957 (Box 27, Folder 136)
  - Noor, Tadjudin, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 137)
  - Notokusumo, R. M., 1955-1960 (Box 27, Folder 138)
  - Nungtjik, A. R., 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 139)
  - Nurjahman, R., 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 140)
  - Oey Hay Djoen, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 141)
    Surname is Djoen; Typescripts (1955)
  - Oja, Sumantri, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 142)
  - Padang, Muhamad, 1956-1958 (Box 27, Folder 143)
  - Padmoseputra, Monsignor Joannes Obrus, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 144)
  - Palar, Lambertus N., 1954 (Box 27, Folder 145)
    Typescript (1954)
  - Palaunsuka, F. C., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 146)
  - Pamudji, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 147)
  - Papare, Silas, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 148)
  - Pardi, Mas, 1956-1958 (Box 27, Folder 149)
  - Pardjaman, Mrs. Djunah, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 150)
  - Partoadiwidjojo, Oter Pardikin, 1956-1961 (Box 27, Folder 151)
    Typescripts (1956; 1959; 1961)
  - Pieter, A. J. M., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 152)
  - Pirngadie, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 153)
  - Piry, Jacob, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 154)
  - Pratamingkusumo, Tumenggung Aria Mohamad Ali, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 155)
  - Prijono, 1954-1957 (Box 27, Folder 156)
  - Purbodiningrat, S., 1963 (Box 27, Folder 157)
  - Rachmat, R. Tjetje Djaja, 1956-1958 (Box 27, Folder 158)
  - Raka, I. Gusti Gde, 1954-1960 (Box 27, Folder 159)
    Typescripts (1954; 1956-7; 1960)
  - Rasjidi, H., 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 160)
  - Razif, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Rochjani, Mohammed, 1952-1956 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Typescripts (1952; 1956)
  - Rumagessan, Machmud, 1956-1958 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Rumambi, Ds. W. J., 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Runturambi, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Rusli, 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Rustamadji, R., 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Sadjarwo, 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Saifuddin, Hadji Muhammad, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Sakirman, 1955-1960 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    Typescripts (1955-6; 1960)
  - Saka, V. B., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Salawati, Charlotte, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Saleh, Abdulaziz, 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Samjono, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Sapija, Mathijs, 1955-1959 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    Typescripts (1955; 1959)
  - Sarbini (Col.), 1956-1964 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    Typescripts (1956; 1964)
  - Sardjan, Mohammad, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Sardjono, Njonja Umi, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Sardjono, S., 1957 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Sartono, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Sastra, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Sastroamidjojo, Dr. Ali, 1954-1957 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    Typescripts (1954; 1957)
  - Satrosatomo, Seobadio, 1954-1960 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Satsodikoro, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Semaun, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Sembiring, Rakut, 1955-1958 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    Typescripts (1955; 1958)
  - Senduk, Huibert, 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Sidartojo, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Siddiq, K. Achmad, 1956-1959 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Siregar, Jahja, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Siregar, Melanthon, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Siwabessy, Dr. Gerrit Augustinus, 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    Typescripts (1956-8; 1960)
  - Sjafiie, Hadji, 1948-1958 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    Typescripts (1956; 1958); manuscript (1948)
  - Sjaichu, Achmad, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Sjamsudin, Udin, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Sjarkawi, 1954-1960 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    Typescripts (1954-7; 1960)
  - Soepardi, 1950-1956 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Somba, D. J., 1957 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Sondakh, Manuel, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Soleman, Mohammad, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Suatmadji, R., 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - Subamia, I Gusti Gde, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - Dr. Subandrio, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Subandrio, Mrs. Hurustiati, 1957-1963 (Box 28, Folder 44)
    Typescripts (1957-8; 1963)
  - Subijakto, 1956-1963 (Box 28, Folder 45)
    Typescripts (1956-7; 1960; 1963)
  - Sudirman, (Col.), 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 46)
  - Sudisman, 1955-1963 (Box 28, Folder 47)
    Typescripts (1955-7; 1963)
  - Sudjito, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 48)
  - Sudjono, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 49)
  - Sugitha I Made, 1957-1963 (Box 28, Folder 50)
    Typescripts (1957; 1963)
  - Suhadi, R., 1956-1959 (Box 28, Folder 51)
    Typescripts (1956-9)
  - Suharto (Col.), 1956-1967 (Box 28, Folder 52)
    Typescripts (1956-7; 1967)
  - Sukanto, R.S., 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 53)
    Typescripts (1955; 1957)
  - Sukardan, 1957-1959 (Box 28, Folder 54)
  - Sukatno, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 55)
  - Sukirman, 1956-1964 (Box 28, Folder 56)
    Typescripts (1956-8; 1964)
  - Sumardjo, 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 57)
  - Sumarno (Master of Laws), 1958 (Box 28, Folder 58)
    Typescript (1958)
  - Sumarno (Sosroatmodjo), 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 59)
  - Sumpena, Miss Njaju Hadji Mariam Kanta, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 60)
  - Sumual, Lt. Col. Herman N. Ventie, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 61)
  - Sunario, Dr., 1954 (Box 28, Folder 62)
  - Sunario, Mrs., 1955 (Box 28, Folder 63)
  - Sunarjo, 1955-1960 (Box 28, Folder 64)
    Typescripts (1955; 1957; 1960)
  - Sungkana, Katja, 1959-1978 (Box 28, Folder 65)
    Typescripts (1959; 1978)
  - Supardo, 1947-1978 (Box 28, Folder 66)
    Typescripts (1947; 1956-9; 1978)
  - Suprapto, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 67)
  - Surjosurarso, Col. Sujarso, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 68)
  - Suroso, R. Pandji, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 69)
  - Suryadarma, R. Suryadi, 1956-1964 (Box 28, Folder 70)
  - Sutarto Hadisudibjo, R.H., 1955-1960 (Box 28, Folder 71)
  - Sutjipto, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 72)
  - Sutomo, 1955-1964 (Box 28, Folder 73)
    Typescripts (1955; 1964)
  - Sutopo, M., 1958 (Box 28, Folder 74)
  - Sutoto, M., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 75)
  - Sutrasno, Mrs. Lastari, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 76)
  - Suwages, Nicholas Luther, 1957-1958 (Box 28, Folder 77)
  - Suwirjo, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 78)
  - Suwito Kusumowidagdo, 1957-1958 (Box 28, Folder 79)
    Surname is Kusumowidago: Typescripts (1957-1958)
  - Suwono, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 80)
  - Talu, Abdulmutalib Daeng, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 81)
  - Tambing, Willem Linggi, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 82)
  - Tambunan, A. M., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 83)
  - Tanamas, Zainal Arifin, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 84)
  - Tan, Ling Djie, 1955-1958 (Box 28, Folder 85)
  - Thaher, S. M., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 86)
  - Thaid, Mrs. Hafni Zahra Abhanifah, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 87)
  - Thajeb, Teuku Moh. Thaher, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 88)
  - Thojib, Hadiwidjaja, 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 89)
  - Tjoo, Tik Tjoen, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 90)
  - Tobing, 1957-1959 (Box 28, Folder 91)
  - Umbas, F., 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 92)
  - Wahib, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 93)
  - Wens, E. F., 1957 (Box 28, Folder 94)
  - Wen, Tony, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 95)
  - Werdojo, Karsono, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 96)
  - Wiriadinata, Lt. Col., 1958 (Box 28, Folder 97)
  - Wiriasumita, Djadja, 1956-1964 (Box 28, Folder 98)
  - Zainal, Abidin Ahmad, 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 99)
  - Zain, Mohammad Anwar, 1956-1974 (Box 28, Folder 100)
    Typescripts (1956; 1974)
  - Daerah (Chiefs of), 1958 (Box 28, Folder 101)
    Government data sheet
  - Film, 1977-1987 (Box 28, Folder 102)
    Typescript draft (1987); scanned typescript (1977)
  - Java Music II, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 103)
    Music diagrams; typescript (1975); various handwritten and typed notes
  - Music/Java, 1955-1976 (Box 28, Folder 104)
    Large notebook of notes; journal publications (1969; 1976); typescripts (1955; 1965; 1973); music diagrams; reprints (1960; 1966); scanned images; various handwritten and typed notes and musical scores; scanned typescript (1970)
  - Play: Papers, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 105)
    Typescript draft (1988)
  - Translations of Kats' Wayang Poerwa, Undated (Box 28, Folder 106)
    (Most likely) personal translations of works
  - Wayang Materials I, 1962-1976 (Box 28, Folder 107)
  - Wayang Materials II, 1964-1972 (Box 28, Folder 108)
    Typescripts (1970); tree diagram; news article (1964; 1972); notes; scanned illustrations; notepad of notes
  - Wayang Photos, Undated (Box 28, Folder 109)
    Images of various sizes
  - CMIP in Indonesia, 1966-1994 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    Scanned typescripts (1966; 1974); typescripts (1972); correspondence (1967; 1972); scanned news article (1994); newspaper clippings (1967-8; 1972; 1994); news publication (1972)
  - Communist Documents: Post Coup, 1965-1977 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    Typescripts (1969); scanned typescript (1965-7; 1977)
  - Coup Foreign Clippings, News Articles, 1965-1970 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    Scanned news articles (1967); typescripts (1967); news publication (1966); newspaper clippings (1965-6; 1970)
  - Coup: Miscellaneous Materials, 1965-1978 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    Typescripts (1965-6); scanned news article (1978); typescript draft
  - Coup: Unprocessed Interviews, 1966-1968 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    Typescript (1966); notes (1967 or 1968)
  - Dhani trial - notes on proceedings, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    Typescript (1966)
  - DN Aidit: Gagalinja G30S, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    Scanned typescript (1965)
  - G. Dem Foreign Policy, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    Typescripts (1965); notes
  - G. 30 S: American Materials, 1962-1976 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    Scanned typescripts (1962; 1964-5; 1976)
  - Killings, 1965-1966 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    Newspapers (1965-6); typescripts, including unpublished papers (1965); correspondence (1965); scanned news articles (1966); news publication (1965)
  - Latoeg Materials, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    Index of names; interview record; scanned typescripts and manuscripts (1978); newspaper clippings (1978)
  - McGeehee on Coup, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    Scanned news article (1981)
  - Ngadimo trials etc., 1966 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    Notes (1966)
  - Njono - Defense Speech, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    Typescripts (1966); documents pertaining to legal trial records, with notes (1966)
  - Nugroho - Saleh draft - Rand text, Undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
    Typescript
  - Official Coup Documents (includes Oudang Report), 1966 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    Typescripts (1966)
  - PKI after 1965, 1965-1969 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    Scanned news articles (1965; 1969)
  - PKI: Biographies, 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    Typescripts (1961); newspaper clipping (1960); notes of political statistical data
  - PKI: Post Coup, 1963-1986 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    Notes (1966; 1979; 1986); scanned typescripts (1963; 1965-6; 1979); scanned news article (1966); correspondence (1965)
  - PKI: Pre-Coup, 1961-1965 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Typescripts (1961); scanned typescripts (1965)
  - Post-Coup Official Speeches and Orders, 1963-1966 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    Government documents (1965-6); scanned typescripts (1963; 1965-6)
  - Post Coup: Official Statements, 1976-1978 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    Scanned news article (1976); news publication (1978)
  - Post Coup Trials - Dhani x others, 1966-1969 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    Notes from newspapers in chronological order; notes (1966); newspaper clipping (1969); trial records (1966)
  - Prisoners, 1966-1986 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    Scanned typescripts (1966-7; 1974-5; 1977); typescripts (1967-9; 1973; 1975; 1978); government documents (1968; 1977); scanned news articles (1969; 1976; 1978-9; 1986); newspaper clippings (1968; 1970; 1972; 1975); correspondence (1966; 1969; 1970); news publication (1974); notes
  - Scanned Newspapers, Typescripts, and Correspondence, 1965-1981 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    Scanned newspapers (1965); scanned news article (1987); scanned typescripts; correspondence (1981)
  - Skrips: Soe Hok Gie, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    Typescript (1985)
  - Soe's thesis/draft, Undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
    Thesis draft with written edits; notes
  - "Special" Coup Sources, 1964-1974 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    Notes; press cables (1965; 1971; 1974); scanned news articles; newspaper clipping (1965)
  - Supardjo Materials, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    Notes; biographical information
  - Sudisman: Otokritik, 1967-1970 (Box 30, Folder 11)